<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="sizhe-li.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="sizhe-li.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-03-17T01:29:33+00:00</updated><id>sizhe-li.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Rethinking Robot Modeling and Representations</title><link href="sizhe-li.github.io/blog/2025/jacobian-fields-tutorial/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rethinking Robot Modeling and Representations"/><published>2025-03-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>sizhe-li.github.io/blog/2025/jacobian-fields-tutorial</id><content type="html" xml:base="sizhe-li.github.io/blog/2025/jacobian-fields-tutorial/"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>Was Du ererbt von Deinen Vätern hast, erwirb es, um es zu besitzen. (Goethe)</p><cite><a class="citation" href="#"></a></cite></blockquote> <h1 id="motivation">Motivation</h1> <p>Conventional robots – rigid links, discrete joints, and precise sensors -— are a historical artifact of control and planning approaches. <strong>How can robots with diverse morphologies, mechanisms, and sensors be represented, modeled, and controlled in a general-purpose way?</strong> Machine learning can enable imprecise, flexible, and unconventional robots to perform as effectively as traditional designs, paving the way for more affordable, adaptable, and mass-produced robots.</p> <p>Achieving this vision requires new control and modeling algorithms that go beyond precise sensor feedback and idealized dynamics. Conventional methods struggle with bio-inspired and soft-rigid hybrid robots, which lack internal sensors and well-defined states. Further, standard definitions of robot actions, such as end-effector pose changes, may not capture the contact-rich and whole-body motions. Finally, general-purpose robot representation offers new perspectives on appendages and tool use, as scissors and hammers function without embedded sensors but can be considered extensions to the robot dynamics upon contacts.</p> <p>These questions demand a multidisciplinary approach. Our research combines computational models (drawing chiefly on machine learning, computational perception, and physics) with unique perspetives from the design and fabrication of bio-inspired robots. Our model, Neural Jacobian Field, could inspire the development of general-purpose models of robot dynamics and the integration of vision, touch, and sound into a unified spatial representation of robotic systems.</p> <p>(Work in progress; 03/16/2025, Lester Li)</p> ]]></content><author><name>Sizhe Lester Li</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[An overview of Neural Jacobian Field, an architecture that autonomously learns to represent, model, and control in general-purpose way.]]></summary></entry></feed>